Kurt Cooney

Marietta, GA 30062 krtcotmo2@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/kurtcooney github.com/krtcotmo2 krtcotmo2.herokuapp.com



Web developer experienced with various aspects of server and client-side scripting practices, extracting complex data from SQL and creating visual representations. Strong focus on problem solving and user experience. Creatively develop graphical interfaces to deliver enterprise wide solutions to help drive business forward. Excel in bridging the gap between technical concepts and lesser technical individuals. Expert in taking small ideas, expanding on the possibilities and designing in long term expand ability.

Technical Skills

Languages:

Node/JavaScript/jQuery ASP.NET C# HTML/CSS SQL/NoSQL DB

Applications:

Visual Studio/VSCode Adobe CC GIT Office

Experience

Senior Developer

InterDev, July 2018 - current

Created numerous tools internally within the company's intranet and for existing clients. Web server configurations, SharePoint administration, reporting services.

Key Accomplishments:

- Improved scheduling efficiency for our services team by Implementing a dashboard with .NET and D3 within ConnectWise bytapping into the backend database. The dashboard illustrates upcoming projects and individual employees work schedules to better plan upcoming work
- Created an online configurator for a counter manufacturing company servicing national big box retailers
- Improved manger labor and billing reporting using SQL and SQL Reporting Services to combine data within various parts of ConnectWise. The new one click reports reduce data compilation by over 60% and helps pinpoint potential missing time entries.

Sr Web Developer, Sr eLearning Developer and eLearning Developer T-Mobile USA, July 2005 - June 2018

Work independently and with cross functional teams to discover issues, solve problems and implement solutions with creative interactions within the enterprise intranet.

Key Accomplishments:

- Implement intake forms for the HR Communications team utilizing .NET, JavaScript, custom RESTful Web Services, SQL and D3. Forms gathered requirements, delivered communications, tracked projected level of effort and displayed team capacity levels in easy to read graphs. Easily illustrated the team's ability to take on new work based on availability
- Create custom dashboards powered by .NET and JSON for multiple business across the enterprise with consideration for responsive design
- Deploy enterprise wide application to communicate the details, value and acceptance of the Founders Grant for every individual in the company with 97% acceptance rate after failed AT&T merger
- Maintain 30+ site collections in SharePoint including manage permissions, custom forms and workflows, design landing pages with dynamic content
- Work corroboratively as a team for sharing best practices
- Test and debug issues across the internal network







Kurt Cooney

Marietta, GA 30062 krtcotmo2@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/kurtcooney github.com/krtcotmo2 krtcotmo2.herokuapp.com



Knowlagent Inc., August 2000 - July 2005

- Created reusable eLearning games with Flash while collaborating with Instructional Designers and Graphics Designers while building effective cohesive courseware
- Develop reusable graphical templates in Photoshop and code snippets in Dreamweaver to expedite the course creation process
- Coach other developers improving techniques
- Designed and delivered training for instructor lead training

Production Artist

Digitek, Inc., March 1999 - November 1999

 Internship supporting several lead graphic designers in the creation of brochures, magazine advertising and business stationary for one and two-color press

Projects

- Developing a MERN stack application for designing countertops and vanities created from various materials. The application allows for customization from the dimensions, to the colors of the materials, to specific vanity bowls and more. Upon completion of the design the tool prices out the item based on the size, materials and location of the store. The role out date for the site is set for later this year and will be utilized in numerous big box home improvement stores across the nation.
- Prototype and develop .NET application supported by SQL database that contributed to saving T-Mobile nearly \$8.5 million in unrecorded PTO.
 Spearheaded development while working closely with administrators of the Kronos software and the communications team to ensure accuracy and ensuring managers understood their role in the project fulfillment.
- Provided a powerful tool for Recruiters, Managers and potential candidates to see the career opportunities within T-Mobile by drawing from over 400,000 job placement records. Custom application with RESTful Web Services illustrated current and former employees various career paths within T-Mobile. D3 technology illustrates the career paths in charts and Sankey diagrams for 1000's of career lifecycles.
- Redesign of national fertilizer manufacturer site for placing and creating custom fertilizer. Refocused the site to become more customer centric and allowed for sales teams to focus on a consultative relationship with the clients opposed to an administrative role.

Education

Georgia Tech, Atlanta, Georgia Full Stack Flex Web Development, May 2019

Art Institute of Atlanta, Atlanta, Georgia Bachelor of Art in Graphic Design, March 2001

University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida Bachelor of Science in Advertising, June 1993

Extended Courses

Xamarin - Mobile App Development Training from ZeoLearn

Other Experience

Publix Supermarkets, February 1985 - March 2003 Extensive roles across the entire store involving teamwork, personnel development, management and leadership





